I'm going to reactivate the video to, let's say,
pretend we're in an
intermodular project.
Eh, of course, first remember that when I
modified the data model of the
ODO module, I had to
re-execute the console command so
that the views and the database would
notice the change in the model, which
would obviously involve taking a script like this and
modifying it, that is, not as direct
as this one of creating the table if it doesn't exist,
but a more elaborate SQL request to see
if the table exists and the model is the same,
respect it.  But if it's not the same, alter
table, I don't know what, I don't know how many.  Okay,
sure, it's no more than 1 RM, I wouldn't
call this 1 RM because it's true
that XML can eventually derive an
object, but we're not even there,
okay?  but more than an ORM it is, well,
throughout the previous course and a
little bit in this course,
we are often saying who is in charge, right?  That
is, in the MVC model, who is the
model?
And I insist that over the months,
we've done examples of a bit of
everything, in the sense that sometimes
the model has been the database,
sometimes the model has been the
form, sometimes the model has
been, who knows what, the
controller never ends up being the
model.
What is the only difference in this
case?  The only difference is that the
model is an external file, say,
a neutral
XML arbiter.  You don't give a damn about XML in the
database, you don't give a damn about XML in the form, you don't give a
damn about XML in everything.  XML knows nothing about
anyone.  XML only knows, I insist, XML,
why did you tell me XML?  Porque estamos
viendo que ODO funciona con XML.  It could have
been JSON, okay?  Or it could have
been a CSV file.
But XML only knows that it defines a
model, they will go find it.  And then, in
fact, the function, the function that
we programmed goes through the XML to
define the database and to define
the view.  Okay?  So now So
now for this part I'm going to pull
Let's see
moment.  Crude, no.  Server that
converts.  Okay, I'm
going to use
artificial intelligence to do some mapping here,
okay?  And I say,
this server
with this interface
eh controller
to my function
with this interface declaration.
Okay.  And interface.
Okay.
Now, eh, modify.
Uh, I don't know.  So, what do we change?
Well I guess that's my role or what.
Yes.
I suppose
my function
to send
receive.
data and save toculite
eh automatically
mapping
eh views and with FQL table
since fields eh are the same,
okay?  as if to say, "Since you've
made a view and a model, a
database with this data, then use it,
okay? Map it. Let's see it for a
moment.
I would save it as my function two. Let's
see.
Okay. Okay.
Moment, moment.
[Music]
Okay, app. Pie. Okay, this
is the table.
Hey, I'm missing a route.
How strange. Okay, well, nothing, let's
see. 007 server
that receives those routes as input
hasn't worked out very well for me, but okay.
And my function p.
Okay, let's call this. Okay, okay,
okay. Ah, look, how nice. Wow, it
's good. How cool. Okay, this is my
function two.
My function 2.p,
okay? And the XML stays the same. Okay?
So, in the server that receives I'm going to
say my function two.
Let's see it. Let's see it. We're
done.
Python 3 eh 00, right? Python 3007.
Okay,
let's see  What's going on? 127 5000.
Formula. Oh, what a nice form. Oh,
[ __ ]. So, first name, last name,
email, address, message. Okay, so to
address and message.
Send, okay? Data saved, go back
to the form, view the table,
and there we have it. Okay? And now go back
to the form. BBB, BBB, BBB, BBB, BBB.
Send, view the table. And there we have it.
But what's going on? Well, what's going on is
that I, okay, now I insist, let me
do it really hard because I don't have one,
because developing the logic for the alter
table would take a lot longer to
program. Developing the logic for the
alter table means altering the
data model, going to the
database, looking at the changes, and
making an alteration based only on the
changes. That would be a pain, okay?
So I'm going to eliminate
the beast, the database, for now. I'm going to go to the
interface and add a
text field called, uh, I don't know, country.  Okay, if
I do this, notice that I stop,
reload,
come here,
and suddenly I have country,
and I have country so much—wait, I should
have closed this before. I have country
both in the form
and if I open it with that little ass, I have
country simply because I just
entered it in the XML, okay? And this is a
bit of the methodology, I insist, not
only of ODO, but, for example,
the methodology of caray, of Django, which
is the creator of this webs for
Python, is exactly the same. You
declare a model in a file, you hit
persist, and from there it creates the
views, creates the models, and creates everything else
that's needed. Okay,
let's stop for 5 minutes, I'm going to go to
the service.